<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Other Features on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/other-features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Other Features on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/other-features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Inline Expression</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/other-features/inline-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/other-features/inline-expression/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Configuration simplicity and unity are two main problems that inline expression intends to solve.
In complex sharding rules, with more data nodes, a large number of configuration repetitions make configurations difficult to maintain. Inline expressions can simplify data node configuration work.
Java codes are not helpful in the unified management of common configurations. Writing sharding algorithms with inline expressions, users can stored rules together, making them easier to be browsed and stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Primary Key</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/other-features/key-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/other-features/key-generator/</guid>
      <description>Motivation In the development of traditional database software, the automatic sequence generation technology is a basic requirement. All kinds of databases have provided corresponding support for this requirement, such as MySQL auto-increment key, Oracle auto-increment sequence and so on. It is a tricky problem that there is only one sequence generated by different data nodes after sharding. Auto-increment keys in different physical tables in the same logic table can not perceive each other and thereby generate repeated sequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharding Hint</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/other-features/sharding-hint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/other-features/sharding-hint/</guid>
      <description>Motivation ShardingSphere can be compatible with SQL in way of parsing SQL statements and extracting columns and values to shard. If SQL does not have sharding conditions, it is impossible to shard without full route.
In some applications, sharding conditions are not in SQL but in external business logic. So it requires to designate sharding result externally, which is referred to as Hint in ShardingSphere.
Mechanism ShardingSphere uses ThreadLocal to manage sharding key values.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>