<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Use Norms on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/use-norms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Use Norms on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/use-norms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/use-norms/sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/use-norms/sql/</guid>
      <description>Since the SQL syntax is flexible and complex and distributed databases and stand-alone databases do not have identical query sceanrios, SQLs incompatible with stand-alone databases are hard to avoid.
This document has listed identified supported SQL types and unsupported SQL types, trying to avoid traps for users.
It is inevitably to have some unlisted SQLs, welcome to supplement for that. We will also try to support those unavailable SQLs in future versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pagination</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/use-norms/pagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/use-norms/pagination/</guid>
      <description>Totally support pagination queries of MySQL, PostgreSQL and Oracle; partly support SQLServer pagination query due to its complexity.
Pagination Performance Performance Bottleneck Pagination with query offset too high can lead to a low data accessibility, take MySQL as an example:
SELECT * FROM t_order ORDER BY id LIMIT 1000000, 10  This SQL will make MySQL acquire another 10 records after skipping 1,000,000 records when it is not able to use indexes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parser</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/use-norms/parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/legacy/4.x/document/en/features/sharding/use-norms/parser/</guid>
      <description>ShardingSphere supports multiple dialects of SQL using different parsers. For specific SQL dialects that do not implement parsers, the default is to use the SQL92 standard for parsing.
Specific SQL dialect parser  PostgreSQL parser
 MySQL parser
 Oracle parser
 SQLServer parser
  Note: MySQL parser supports MySQL, H2, and MariDB dialect.
Default SQL dialect parser Other SQL dialects, such as SQLite, Sybase, DB2 and Informix, are parsed by default using the standard of SQL92.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>